原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     白夜君  草草  苏葵  小酸奶
校对     小酸奶
时间轴     西查
后期     吉吉
总监     小酸奶
深入黑暗  第一季 第八集
你没事吧  还好吧
You okay? It's all right?
我在哪
Where am I?
你在我的房间里
You're in my room.
我好冷
I'm cold.
你是谁
Who are you?
演奏我们的歌曲
Play our song.
你喜欢红酒的
You like wine.
是吗
Do I?
我在努力
I'm trying.
但是...
But, um...
什么都记不得
There's nothing.
一点也不吗
Nothing?
不记得
No.
我们相遇的那晚也不记得吗
Not even the night we met?
我们相遇的那晚
The night we met?
我们摧毁的一切
完事了
It's done.
斯宾塞
我回头写
I'll get to it.
感觉有什么不同吗
Did it feel any different?
好吧
Fine.
我给你写下来
I'll write it down for you.
没有
And no.
感觉完全不像她
Didn't feel anything like her.
呼入  帕克
地点未知
怎么样了
How's it going?
我在尽我所能帮他
I'm doing everything I can to help him
他却毫无反馈
and he gives me nothing.
你还要再做吗
So are you going to do it again?
他需要帮助
He needs help.
我就是在帮他
That's what I'm doing.
临床治疗
Clinical help.
他们会把他夺走
They'll take him from me.
那就很糟吗
Would that be so terrible?
我担心  小维
I'm worried, Vic.
-我可以保护他  -那你呢
- I can protect him. - What about you?
你要为他做到什么程度
I mean, how far are you willing to go for him?
你在他的那本日记里是永远找不到全部真相的
He'll never give you the whole truth in that journal of his.
你得亲眼看到他那么做才能理解
You need to see him in the act to understand.
我不能
I can't.
你知道我观察实验
You know I can't observe the experiment
会影响结果
without altering the results.
扯淡的借口
Bullshit excuse.
就算有观察偏倚
Even with observation bias,
亲眼观察也能比转述获取更多准确数据
the firsthand accounting yields more accurate data than hearsay.
怎么观察
How?
录下他
Record him.
留下证据链吗
And create a chain of evidence?
用直播信号
Start a live feed.
只有这样才能真正知道
It's the only way to really know.
你是她吗
Are you her?
你是别人吗
Are you someone else?
-我是我吧  -你确定吗
- I'm me? - Are you sure?
我不知道
I don't know.
你还记得我吗
Do you even remember me?
-不  -记起我
- No. - Remember me!
演奏我们的歌曲
Play our song.
我想走
I want to go.
信号丢失
滚下我的车
Get the fuck out of my car.
-滚出来  -你不能丢下我
- Get the fuck out of here.  - You can't fucking leave me!
-滚开  -我都不知道我在哪
- Fuck off! - I don't know where the fuck I am!
汤米
Tommy!
去你的
Fuck you!
你个混蛋
You piece of shit.
搞什么
What the fuck?
该死
Fuck!
妈妈在追踪你的位置
你要接近半英里地标了  你在散步吗
对
我要工作到很晚  我希望你天黑前回家
把我丢在这荒无人烟的地方
Left me out here in the middle of nowhere
还不给我电话
without a fucking phone.
我发誓  如果我再见到你
I swear to God if I ever see you again,
我一定要杀了你
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
该死的混蛋
Fucking dick!
混蛋  我发誓
Piece of shit. I swear to God.
该死
Shit.
抱歉
Sorry.
无意吓到你的
Didn't meant to startle you.
你知道你走错路了吧
You know you're goin' the wrong way?
你怎么知道我要往哪走
How do you know which way I'm going?
你在步行  如果你继续往那边走
Well, you're on foot, so... if you keep goin' that way,
你要在黑夜里走一宿了
you're gonna be walking in the dark all night.
好吧  但你怎么走到这儿的
Yeah, but how'd you get here?
我住在那边半英里的地方
I live about half mile that way.
那边还有什么东西吗
Is there anything else that direction?
有个小镇
I mean, there's a town,
但那要走六个小时
but that's, like, a six-hour walk.
你有车吗
You got a car?
没有
No.
那看来我们得去你家了
Well, I guess we're going to your place then.
不行吗
Is that a problem?
没事
That's all right.
好
Okay.
冻死我了
It's fucking freezing.
你要把你的外衣借给我吗
You gonna give me your jacket or?
好  抱歉
Oh, yeah, sorry.
给
Here.
你叫什么
You got a name?
斯宾塞
Spencer.
我是艾什莉
I'm Ashley.
这样不行
This isn't working.
感觉不...
It just doesn't feel--
为什么
Why?
-为什么不行  -因为这太扯了
- Why isn't it working?  - Because it's bullshit.
是假的
It's fake.
我在努力了  斯宾塞  真的
I am trying, Spencer, I really am,
但如果你不帮我  我就不能帮你
but if you don't help me, I can't help you.
这才是第四次尝试
This is only our fourth attempt,
我并不想一直把你关在这里
and I don't want to keep you locked up in here,
但如果你再出去
but if you go out again and...
我不想失去你
I don't want to lose you.
再给我点时间吧
Just give me a little more time.
好
Okay.
你个该死的
God damn you.
我不需要看到那个
I didn't need to see that.
你需要
Yes, you did.
你想帮忙满足他的需要
You want to help satisfy his needs.
以免他真杀掉什么人
Keep him from killing anybody real.
那你就需要看到他那么做
Then you need to witness him in the act.
你只是想让我有负罪感
You just wanted to make me feel guilty.
像个共犯
Complicit.
-你不是吗  -我需要你的建议
- Aren't you? - I need your advice.
他也是你的责任
He's your responsibility too.
你了解到了什么
What did you learn?
你看到了什么
What did you see?
他是对的
He's right.
不够真实
It's not real enough.
能达到那个真实度吗
Will it ever be enough
让他不去再杀别人
to keep him from killing someone else?
泰勒  呼入
你要怎么
What are you going to do
让下一个更真实
to make the next one more real?
我要多花点时间陪她
I'm going to spend more time with her,
给她关注  同情心
give her attention, compassion.
你能在模拟物上投入多少时间
How much time can you give the analogue
而不影响你的工作
without interfering with your work?
这就是我的工作
This is my work.
我是指哈里斯基因的工作
I mean Harris Genetics.
你的公司
You know, your company?
我的公司就要推出
My company is about to roll out
世界首个定制克隆器官了
the world's first custom-grown cloned organs.
我们将完全占有器官移植行业
We're going to own the transplant business.
但他们发现了你的缺席  是吧
But they have noticed your absence, yes?
如果我是个男人
If I were a man,
他们就会说我是古怪或天才
they'd call me an eccentric or a genius.
而不是一个保护欲过度的母亲吗
Instead of an overprotective mother?
我们能说句话吗
Can we have a word?
她好了吗
Is she done?
它...她在客卧
It-- she's in the guest bedroom.
我想让她在那里待会儿
And I'd like to keep her there for a while,
与你隔绝开
away from you.
我觉得那会大有帮助
I think it would be really helpful.
这房子很大
It's a big house.
跟她保持距离应该不难
It shouldn't be too hard to stay away from her.
但我想给她到处走动的
But I want her to have the freedom
自由
to move around.
你乖乖在屋里待着
So stay put here in your room.
你可以画画  看电影
You can draw, watch movies.
你可以去散步
You can go for walks.
只要给我点时间
Anything to give me a little time
让艾什莉
to help Ashley be...
更真实
more real for you.
好
Okay.
难以置信
I can't believe that.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你就打算傻站在那里吗
Are you just gonna stand there?
好吧  抱歉
Right, yeah, sorry.
康奈尔夫妇搬走了吗
Did the Cornells move out?
我父母吗  没
My folks? No.
他们去欧洲避暑了
They're just in Europe for the summer.
严格讲我在替他们看房
Technically I'm watching the place for them
不是搬回家住
and not moving back home.
但感觉起来就是这样
But that's exactly what it feels like.
我刚离开学校
I just left school.
我上了法学院
I was in law school.
我本以为我很想帮助他人
You know, I thought that I really wanted to help people,
但我觉得我其实只想做点有创意的事
but I think actually I just want to do something creative.
知道吗
You know?
嗯
Yeah.
我真混蛋
I'm such a jerk.
你在帮我
Here you are helping me,
我还没问你的名字呢
and I haven't even asked you your name yet.
我是玛丽莎
I'm Marissa.
斯宾塞
Spencer.
好  你住这附近吗
Cool, do you live around here?
嗯  在那边半英里的地方
Yeah, I live about half mile that way.
好
Oh, good.
我很高兴有人住这里
I'm glad somebody lives out here.
我本来还有点慌张
I was getting a little freaked out
这里会只有我
that I'd be here by myself.
你要接吗
You need to get that?
不
No.
就是我妈
It's just my mom.
她每天打来查岗
She calls every day to check in.
挺烦人的
It's kind of annoying.
我没耽误你什么吧
I'm not keeping you from anything, am I?
没有
No, I'm-- no.
你可以帮我
Would you maybe be able to help me
把剩下的东西搬进屋里吗
get the rest of this stuff in the house?
嗯  当然
Yeah, that's-- that's fine.
好啊
Okay, cool.
你可以搬下那个吗
If you could just grab that stuff.
你是斯宾塞的妈妈吧
You must be Spencer's mom.
是的
Yes.
怎么了
Why?
他在吗  我为他做了这些饼干
Is he here? I made these cookies for him.
抱歉  我无意失礼  但...
I'm sorry, I don't mean to be rude, but--
他今天帮我搬家来着
He helped me get moved in today.
我是玛丽莎·康奈尔
I'm Marissa Cornell.
我父母的房子就在路那边
My folks own the place down the road.
斯宾塞
Spence!
我并不想占用
Well, listen, I don't want to take up
你们太多时间
a bunch of your time or anything.
我只是想以此感谢你帮我忙
I just made these to show my appreciation for all the help.
你儿子太好心了
Your son's awfully nice.
多谢你这么说
That's very nice of you to say.
那好吧
Okay, well,
我还要收拾东西
I've got some boxes to unpack,
那我就不打扰了
so I'll leave you be.
回见了  斯宾塞
See you later, Spence.
认识你很高兴
It was nice to meet you.
你怎么想的
What the fuck are you thinking?
就是几个箱子  妈妈
It was just a few boxes, Mom.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
她还给他做了饼干
She made him cookies.
看来别想让他远离世界了
So much for keeping him away from the world.
她什么样
What's she like?
话痨
Bubbly.
你觉得他盯上她了吗
And you think he's fixating on her?
他在画她
He's drawing her.
新的模拟物怎么样了
How's the new analogue?
我本来在纠结怎么让它感觉更真实
I was struggling with how to make it feel more real
然后我想到了
when it occurred to me
她已经有背景故事了
she already has a backstory.
我可以给她看她此前生活的部分片段
I can show her select pieces of her previous life.
整理好的历史
A curated history.
很有效
And it's working.
她看上去像人了
She seems human.
斯宾塞
Spencer!
真是好惊喜
What a nice surprise.
来还你的盘子的
Just came to return your plate.
好啊
Cool.
进来吧
Come on in.
来吧
Come on.
你喜欢饼干吗
Did you like the cookies?
喜欢  挺好吃的
Yeah, they were-- they were good.
你拿了什么
What you got there?
就是给你的回礼
Uh, it's just a little something for you.
我画的
I drew it.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
喜欢
Yeah.
画得太好了
This is amazing.
你说想要做些有创意的事  所以
You just said you wanted to do something creative. So...
嗯
Yeah.
我看出来了
Yeah, I totally see it.
太酷了
This is so cool.
谢谢
Thank you.
我都不知道你这么有才
I had no idea that you were so talented.
你应该为我设计一个纹身
You should design a tattoo for me.
我一直想纹一个
I've always wanted one.
我想纹在这里
I think I want to do it, like, right here.
这样就能随时藏起来
So I can hide it if I want to.
也许我会纹这个蝴蝶
Maybe I'll do that butterfly.
因为我总在改变
You know, 'cause I'm always changing.
蝴蝶只蜕变一次
A butterfly only changes once.
没错
Oh yeah.
你说得对
You're right.
我喜欢你
I like you.
你好奇怪
You're weird.
你去哪了
Where have you been?
你知道的
You know where.
玛丽莎家
Marissa's.
我以为之前说清楚了
I thought I made myself clear.
你不能去见她
You are not to see her.
你想要我怎么样
What do you want me to do?
你想要我正常点
You want me to act normal?
这就是我正常的样子
This is-- this is me acting normal, okay?
我在交朋友
I'm makin' friends.
你不希望我出现在你眼前  又不想我出门
You don't want me around, you don't want me to go out.
我不是不希望你出现在我眼前
It's not that I don't want you around.
斯宾塞  我在她身上下的功夫都是为了你
Spencer, I'm doing all of this work on her for you!
你想见她吗
Do you want to meet her?
好吧
Fine.
明天
Tomorrow.
我帮你准备一下她
Let me get her ready for you.
老天  这地方真不错
Shit, this place is great.
你一个人住吗
You, uh, live here alone?
不  我和我妈一起
No, I live here with my mom.
她在家吗
Is she home?
不  她去工作了
No, she's at work.
是吗
Yeah?
她是干什么的
What does she do?
基因学家
She's a geneticist.
你不能进去
Hey, you can't go in there.
这是她的实验室
That's her lab.
好吧
Okay.
你认识之前和你在一起的那人吗
Hey, you know that guy you were with?
认识
Yeah.
去他的
Fuck him.
他对我来说已经死了
He's fucking dead to me.
我能去厕所吗  需要小便
Can I get a bathroom? Need to piss.
就在那边
It's right over there.
我能来点吗
Can I?
当然
Yeah, sure.
那么
So...
就我们俩了
We're alone.
你不来点吗
Aren't you gonna join me?
当然  我...
Yeah, I-- I...
我也来点
I can do that.
有什么
So is there, like...
你能联系的人或什么的吗
anybody you need to call or anything like that?
没有
No.
我就需要到城镇上就行
I just need to get to town.
任何城镇都行
You know, any town, really.
等我妈回来了我能载你一程
But I can give you a ride when my mom gets back home.
你妈妈什么时候回来
When can we expect Mom?
大概再有几个小时吧
Probably not for another hour or so.
我们该怎么打发这段时间
So how should we kill a few hours?
你有音乐吗
Do you have any music?
直接说就行
Just ask.
播放宝贝们的歌
Play The Babys?
我喜欢这首歌
I... I love this song.
我奶奶以前
My grandma, she used to, uh--
以前经常放这歌
she used to play it all the time.
我觉得她想  我也说不好
I think she wanted to, I don't know,
想睡了乐队的主唱吧
fuck the lead singer or something?
你的房间在这边吗
Is your room down here?
是的
Uh, yeah.
你还记得我提起过我儿子吧
You remember me mentioning my son, yes?
是他找到我的
He's the one who found me.
我觉得你俩该见见了
I think it's time the two of you met.
斯宾塞很害羞
Spencer is very shy.
能使他敞开心扉的
The best way to get him to open up
最好方法就是谈谈他喜欢的事物
is to talk to him about things he enjoys.
他喜欢什么
What does he like?
他喜欢艺术和音乐
He likes art and music.
喜欢红酒和自然
He's fond of wine and nature.
告诉他你们爱好相同
Tell him you like the same things.
问问他画的画
Ask him about his art.
好的
Okay.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我挺好的
I'm fine.
我们去见他吧
Let's go meet him, shall we?
艾什莉  我想让你见见我儿子斯宾塞
Ashley, I'd like to introduce you to my son Spencer.
你想喝点红酒吗
Would you like some wine?
乐意至极  谢谢
Yeah, I'd love some. Thank you.
我让你俩好好熟悉熟悉吧
Well, I will leave the two of you to get better acquainted.
你妈妈说你喜欢艺术音乐之类的
Your mom told me that you like art and music and stuff like that?
是的
Yeah.
我也喜欢音乐
I like music too.
演奏我们的歌曲
Play our song.
这是你画的吗
Did you do this?
是的
I did.
很美
It's beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你还有其他的作品吗
Do you have more you could show me?
这些太棒了
These are great.
你认识我多久了
How long have you known me?
在你变成你之前
Since before you were even you.
你没有写
You're not writing.
怎么了
What is it?
每天早上我起来  感觉周围一切都很假
Every morning I get up and everything seems fake.
我看到  摸到的一切都很...
It's like everything I see and everything I touch just...
感觉不真实
doesn't feel real.
彷佛我和世界之间隔着一层膜
Like there's a membrane between me and the rest of the world.
有时膜慢慢逼近
And sometimes that membrane closes in
我都无法呼吸
and I feel like I can't breathe.
就好像我被这种
Like I'm being smothered by this...
恐怖无形的虚空扼住了喉咙
horrible invisible nothingness.
但今天我觉得自己能呼吸了
But today I felt like I could breathe.
我已经很久没感觉这么好
And I haven't felt this good,
这么自由  自从...
this free, since...
这是头一回
well, the first time.
我...
Well, I...
我不想写下来
I didn't want to write that down.
我想告诉你
I wanted to tell you.
你知道我有多感激
You know how thankful I am.
他真的抱了你
He actually hugged you?
身体接触
Real physical contact?
他已经很多年没拥抱我了
It's been years since he's done that.
奏效了
It's working.
这个突破可能带来
This breakthrough could lead to
一种全新的行为矫正法
an entirely new kind of behavior modification therapy.
而应用将会
The applications could be--
你的公司花费了数年
The years it took your company
才批准了一个克隆器官的移植项目
to gain approval simply to clone organs for transplant.
-我知道  -原教旨主义者已经
- I know. - Fundamentalists still want
想为此把你烧了
to burn you at the stake for that.
我很清楚还没有人准备好
I'm well aware that nobody is ready to debate
为人类克隆的合法性和伦理性辩护
the legalities and ethics of human cloning,
但这效果太好了
but the effects!
那现在怎么办
So what now?
先等一段时间
Now, we let some time pass,
看这个良效能持续多久
see how long the positive effects last,
然后再做一次  做得更好
then do it again, better.
他们相处的时间越愉快
The more satisfying the event,
就能持续地更久  然后
the more time can pass between them, and then...
也许他能搬出去
maybe he can move out.
去念大学
Go to college.
拥有自己的生活
Have a life.
等他瘾复发时再回来
Return home whenever he needs his fix.
你好  斯宾塞
Heya, Spence.
玛丽莎
Marissa.
你在慢跑
You're jogging.
是啊  我讨厌慢跑
Yeah, I hate it.
那你为什么跑
Then why do you do it?
因为在这无事可做
'Cause there's nothing else to do out here
所以我想保持下体型
so I figured I might as well get in shape.
你怎么能受得了
How do you stand it?
受得了什么
Stand what?
这种安静
The quiet.
我喜欢安静
I like it.
能让我思考
Lets me think.
我思考得太多
I think too much.
我总是沉浸在自己的想法里
I'm always in my head and...
过度分析
overanalyzing and...
我的心理医生以前常这么说
That's what my therapist used to say.
你去看心理医生吗
You see a therapist?
是啊  现在人人都去
Yeah, doesn't everybody?
那你  那你都说些什么
What do you-- what do you talk about?
就是  你为什么去看心理医生
Like, what do you-- what do you see her for?
我以前有饮食紊乱症
I had an eating disorder.
无法接受自己的身体什么的
Poor body image, stuff like that.
我以前觉得自己
I used to think that I was, like,
活得很糟糕而且很古怪
like, really messed up and weird,
但我去了学校
but then I went to school
发现所有人都有严重的毒瘾
and everybody there has, like, a crazy drug problem,
我就觉得自己其实还挺正常
so I was like, "I'm actually-- I'm okay."
然后我就不去了
And I just stopped going.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
你也有饮食紊乱症
You had an eating disorder too?
不是  我不再去见心理医生了
No, I--I stopped going to therapy.
你受了什么创伤
What's your damage?
斯宾塞  抱歉  你无需
Spence, I'm sorry, you don't--
不  对不起  我不是故意
No, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to--
不不  是我的错
No, no, no, no, it's my fault.
我不该打探
I shouldn't have pried.
其实  我想问你些事情
I actually-- um, I wanted to ask you something.
我正四处找事做  因为太无聊
I was looking for things to do because, you know, bored,
城里的画廊有一场新的展览
and, uh, the gallery in town has a new exhibit coming, and...
我想既然你是位出色的艺术家
I thought that since you're such an amazing artist,
也许你想去看看
that maybe you would wanna go.
你懂的
You know,
和我一起
with me.
考虑下吧
Think about it.
告诉我你的决定
Let me know how you feel.
拜拜
Okay, bye.
这些真的很酷  哥们
These are really cool, dude.
你画的吗
Did you do these?
是的  是我画的
Yeah, those are mine.
我喜欢艺术
I love art.
看
See?
乌洛波洛斯
Ouroboros.
什么
What?
这是它的名字
That's what it's called.
真的吗
Really?
酷
Cool.
不  我不会跳舞
No, I-- I don't dance.
你当然会
Oh, sure you do.
你不经常带女孩来这  是吧
You don't bring a lot of girls up here, do you?
你是第一个
You're the first.
我觉得自己从没成为过谁的第一个
I don't think I've been anyone's first anything before.
放松  小子
Easy, tiger.
别太激动了
Don't wanna get too worked up.
不
No!
操
Fuck!
该死
Fuck.
放开我
Let go of me!
我们这次要耐心点  好吗
We're going to be patient again, right?
好的
Right.
我想让她对你来说更真实
I want her to be real for you,
更像是真的人
to feel like the real thing
延迟你
so you can go longer
冲动爆发的时间
before feeling these urges.
我知道
I know.
-是吗  -我知道  妈妈
- Do you? - I know, Mom.
我明白  我知道我们在做什么
I get it, I understand what we're doing here.
谢谢
Thank you.
早上好
Good morning.
你今天感觉怎么样
How are you feeling today?
如果你感到晕头转向  这是正常的
It's okay if you're feeling disoriented.
你经历了许多事
You've been through a lot.
我在哪里
Where am I?
你出了一场意外
You had an accident,
但我把你修好了
but I patched you up,
你现在应该和新的一样了
and you should be as good as new.
我叫维多利亚
My name is Victoria.
我是基因学家  但我也是结构工程师
I'm a geneticist, but I'm also an MD.
我叫什么
What's my name?
艾什莉
Ashley.
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
我给你做了点汤
I made you some soup.
我什么时候能回家
When can I go home?
你记得你的家在哪里吗
Do you remember where your home is?
别担心
Don't worry,
你的记忆会恢复的
your memories will come back,
只要一恢复
and just as soon as they do,
你就可以回家了  好吗
you can go home, okay?
好的
Okay.
吃得应该差不多了
Well, that's probably enough for now, hmm?
你先休息一下
Why don't you get some more rest,
我们等会儿再聊
and we can talk more later.
好吧
Okay.
维多利亚
Victoria.
怎么了
Yes?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气  艾什莉
You're very welcome, Ashley.
给你
Here.
你给我买了条狗吗
You got me a dog?
谢谢  妈妈  我爱你
Thanks, Mom, I love you.
我也爱你  宝贝
Oh, I love you too, sweetie.
这是谁
Who is that?
这是我儿子  斯宾塞
That's my son, Spencer.
他当时七岁
He was seven years old there.
他现在已经长大了
He's grown up now.
他在和他的第一条狗  马克斯玩
Here, he's playing with our first dog, Max.
你有狗吗
You have a dog?
在哪里
Where is he?
它在这里
He's right here.
马克斯
马克斯死了
Max died.
发生了什么
What happened?
它出了场意外
He had an accident.
它伤得很重
He was hurt very badly,
但它很想活着
but he really wanted to live,
它挣扎了一个星期才去世
and he fought hard for a week before he passed away.
我们把它埋在了这里
We buried him here.
幸运
幸运也死了吗
Lucky died too?
万物都会死
Everything dies.
总有一天  我也会死
One day I'll die.
你也会死
You'll die.
然后呢  会发生什么
And then what, what happens?
没什么
Nothing.
总有一天  你的心脏会停止跳动
One day, your heart will stop beating,
你的大脑得不到
your brain will no longer get the oxygen that it needs
维持工作所需要的氧气
to continue functioning, and...
你身体里的所有东西都会消失
everything that made you you will be gone.
你所有的记忆  经历
All your memories, experiences,
将和你一起死去
will die with you.
为什么
Why?
万事就是这样
It's simply the way things are.
马克斯很清楚
Max knew that.
他为了存活在这个世上而努力挣扎
He fought so hard to stay alive.
每一口呼吸
Every breath
都是珍贵的
is precious.
每场死亡都是悲剧
Every death a tragedy.
谁在和你在一起
Who's here with you?
我以为你变好了
I thought you were better.
你为什么不跟我说说
Why couldn't you talk to me about this?
你为什么对我撒谎
Why did you lie to me?
我不...
I didn't--
我不想让你恨我
I didn't want you to hate me.
她从哪里来的
Where did she come from?
她被困在了路边
She was just stranded on the side of the road.
该死  斯宾塞
Damn it, Spencer.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们得让她消失
We have to make this go away.
怎么弄
How?
我不知道
I don't know.
你什么意思  我们该做什么
What do you mean, what are we supposed to do?
让我想想
Just-- just... let me think.
没人知道她在这里吗
Nobody knows that she's here?
没有  没有
No, no.
好吧
Okay.
好
我可以去实验室
I can go to the lab,
取一个装满吡哆醇的还原罐
get a reduction tank full of pyridoxine,
把她完全分解了
break her down to raw materials.
不会留下任何可以识别的踪迹
There won't be anything recognizable left.
我以为你会喜欢
I thought you'd like this.
穿上吧
Oh, here.
真贴心  谢谢你
That's so sweet, thank you.
我其实应该谢谢你
I should be thanking you actually.
我之前从没亲眼看过艺术品
I've never seen real art in person before.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you joking?
没有
No.
我只是难以相信
That's just so hard for me to believe.
你是个很棒的艺术家
You're such an amazing artist.
你真的可以开自己的画展
You could seriously have your own gallery show.
我不知道  我只看过
I don't know, I've seen virtual tours
罗浮宫和古根海姆博物馆的虚拟游
of the Louvre and Guggenheim,
但仅此而已
but that's about it.
真的吗  你的班级旅行
Really, you never took a class trip
从来没去过博物馆之类的吗
to a museum or anything?
我只上到了小学六年级  所以...
I was only in school till sixth grade, so...
为什么
Why?
自此之后  我妈都在家里教我
Mom home-schooled me after that
然后我们搬到了这里
and moved us out here,
一直把我关在家里
kept me on a leash.
大家都说这样最好
Everyone said it was for the best.
他们为什么这么说
Why would they say that?
我在课间做了一些错事
I did something wrong at recess.
我们当时都在攀爬架上玩"山中之王"
We were all playing King of the Mountain on the jungle gym,
你记得那游戏吗
you remember that game?
记得
Yeah.
我一般不会经常和其他孩子们玩
I didn't really play with the other kids that much.
并不是他们...
It's not that they--
他们不想让我玩  或是怎么样
they didn't want me to or anything like that.
只是我不想玩
It's just I didn't feel like it.
我总是看书或是在书上画画
You know, I'd always read or draw in my books.
但当时我觉得那个游戏我好像也可以玩
But I don't know, it seemed like a game that I could get into.
因为很简单
You know, it's simple.
它不需要团队协作
It didn't require any team effort
或是依赖其他人
or dependency on other people.
你只需要爬到顶上  你就是"王"了
You just... climb to the top and you're king, and...
我想当"王"
I wanted to be king.
所以我爬到了攀爬架的顶上
So I climbed to the top of the jungle gym, and...
特蕾西·海因茨就在我的后面
That's when Tracey Heinz got up behind me, and...
我知道这么做不对  但出于某种原因
I knew it was wrong, but for some reason,
那并不重要
that didn't matter.
时间好像静止了一样
It was like time stopped.
这一瞬间...
I was given this moment to...
我能自己做决定
make a decision all on my own, and...
我是唯一掌控一切的人
I was the only one in control.
所以我用力推了她
So I shoved her, hard.
她摔下去了
She fell.
几天之后她死了  他们就
She died a couple days later, and they just
不让我回学校了
didn't let me go back to school, so.
天哪  你当时只是个孩子
God, you were just a kid.
从那之后你就远离你的同龄人吗
And you've been away from people your own age ever since?
我妈说这样最好
My mom said it was for the best, so.
过来  我想给你看点东西
Come here, I want to show you something.
惊喜
Surprise!
这家画廊的老板是我朋友的朋友
The gallery owner is a friend of my folks,
我给他看的时候  他吓了一跳  斯宾塞
and he freaked out when I showed it to him, Spence.
他说如果你有更多的作品
He said that if you have more like this,
你可以办自己的画展了
then you can have your own show.
斯宾塞
Spencer!
我没有送给他
I didn't give it away to him,
这不是拿来卖的
and it's not for sale.
我永远不会把它送人的
I would never give this piece away.
我没让你这么做
I didn't ask you to do this.
我不明白在你这么做之前
I-I don't understand why you'd do this
为什么不问问我
without asking me.
为了给你个惊喜
To surprise you.
斯宾塞  你是个艺术家
Spencer, you're an artist.
你属于这里
You belong here.
我只是想让你看到这点
I just wanted you to see that.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
斯宾塞  你还没睡吗
Spencer, you still up?
斯宾塞
Spencer?
你想定位谁
斯宾塞
正在定位斯宾塞
妈妈
手机已定位
我决定了
I've decided something.
你要跟我多出去玩几次
You are going out more, with me.
我强迫你去
I'm gonna force you.
因为你被关在那房子里太久了
Because you've been cooped up in that house for way too long,
而你需要多体验世界
and you need to have more experiences.
你知道的
And, you know,
我需要干点事情
I need things to do.
很高兴我能缓解你的无聊
Well, I'm glad I can assuage your boredom.
不是  不是这个
No, stop it, no, it's not just that.
我觉得你真的很棒
I think that you're really cool.
以前从来没人这么说过
No one's ever called me that before.
晚安
Good night.
你去哪儿了
Where have you been?
我们在美术馆里  妈妈
We were at an art gallery, Mom.
我还要跟你说几遍...
How many times do I have to tell you--
我现在不能有朋友吗
I can't have friends now?
不  你不能
No, you can't.
你能吗
Can you?
斯宾塞
Spencer,
我是唯一一个
I am the only one
曾经在你身边
who has ever been there for you,
以及一直都会在你身边的人
who will always be there for you.
没人会像我这样照顾你
No one will take care of you the way that I do.
你真的想为了她而毁掉
Do you really want to throw all that away...
这一切吗
for her?
和她在一起感觉不一样
It just feels different with her.
艾什莉
Ashley?
你在外面干什么
What are you doing out here?
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep.
我做了噩梦
I had bad dreams.
真的吗
Really?
梦到什么了
What about?
我无法呼吸
I couldn't breathe.
就像溺水似的吗
Like you were drowning?
不  我...
No, I, um,
我不在水下  只是无法呼吸
I wasn't underwater, I just-- I couldn't breathe,
有双手...
and then there were hands, and...
有人和你在一起吗
Was someone with you?
我不记得了
I don't remember,
但我在另一间卧室
but I was in a different bedroom, and...
我无法呼吸  非常疼痛
I couldn't breathe, and then everything hurt,
然后我就晕过去了
and-- and then it just went black.
只是个梦而已
It's just a dream.
你儿子为什么躲着我们
Why is your son hiding from us?
斯宾塞
Spencer?
他只是很害羞
He's just very shy.
在意外之后
He was the one who found you
是他找到了你
after the accident.
是他照顾了你
He was the one who took care of you.
我不记得了
I-- I don't remember any of that.
你身上肯定发生了什么事
Something must have happened to you.
你当时很混乱  很冷
You were... confused and cold.
你不记得了吗
You don't remember any of that?
不记得了
No.
我什么时候才能好起来
When am I gonna get better?
我在这里做的所有事
Everything I'm doing here
都是为了帮助你恢复
is to help you recover your past.
你只需要耐心一点
You just have to be patient.
需要多久
For how long?
你不能管这叫记忆
You can't call it a memory.
这是场梦
It was a dream.
一个无法呼吸的梦
A dream about not being able to breathe.
她说她就在那个
She said she was in his room
他把她掐死一次又一次的房间里
right where he has choked her to death
她无法呼吸
over and over again, and she couldn't breathe.
-别这样  小维  -要是你能亲眼
- Come on, Vic. - If you were there,
看看她的眼神  她很害怕
if you had seen her eyes, she was so afraid.
我知道她想起来了之前的肉身
I know she is remembering a previous incarnation.
你对模拟物投入的感情太深了
You're growing too attached to the analogue.
它不是模拟物  它是艾什莉
It's not an analogue, it's Ashley.
我跟你说
I'm telling you.
她要想起来她是谁了
She's remembering who she was.
-怎么想  -我不知道
- How? - I don't know!
也许还原过程有净化作用
Maybe there's something purifying in the reduction process.
也许记忆编码在她的DNA中
Maybe memory is encoded in her DNA.
也许上帝因为我们杀人
Maybe God is punishing us
而惩罚我们  创造了这个怪物
for taking a life and creating this abomination.
我不知道  我不知道事情会发展成什么样
I don't know, I don't know how this can be.
没有对照组
There's no control group,
没有先例
there's no precedent for this.
我只知道
All I know is...
她不仅只是一个复制体
she is more than just a copy.
她对你来说更像是真人
She's more real to you?
是的
Yes.
你愿意将她
And you're okay with giving her--
将艾什莉给他
with giving Ashley to him?
我愿意为我的儿子做一切
I would do anything for my son.
你是暗指我不会吗
You're implying that I wouldn't?
毕竟你根本不在这里  对吗
Well, you're not here, are you?
我无法在那里
I can't be there.
你知道的
You know that.
没关系
It's all right,
反正他从来就不需要他的父亲
he's never really needed his father anyway.
艾什莉  我给你做了点午餐...
Ashley, I made you some lunch if--
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Fine.
我没事
I'm fine.
我只是
I just...
又做了一个梦
had another dream.
别担心  噩梦伤不了你
Don't worry, dreams can't hurt you.
你可以好好休息
You can rest all you like.
我待会儿再来看你
I'll come check on you later.
好吗
Okay?
好  谢谢你
Great, thank you.
她在吗
Is she around?
她在她的房间里
She's in her room.
我们能谈谈吗
Can we talk for a second?
关闭音乐
Music off.
好的
Okay.
我觉得我不想再这样下去了
I don't think I wanna do this anymore.
怎样
What exactly?
这一切  她
Just this, her,
这所有的...所有的一切
just the whole-- the whole thing.
你想和我说什么
What are you trying to tell me?
我只想做个正常人  我想和其他人一样
I just want to be normal, I want to be like everybody else
我想拥有普通的人生
and I wanna have a normal life.
我想去交朋友  和他们一起玩
I wanna go make friends and hang out with them.
斯宾塞
Spencer.
你做不到
You can't.
为什么
Why not?
你都看过了多少医生
How many doctors have you seen?
你的冷漠
The detachment,
虐待动物
the animal cruelty,
操场意外
the playground.
这不是一天两天的事了  也不会就此结束
This didn't just start, and it won't just end.
但是为什么不行呢  我...
Okay, but why not? Like, I--
这不就是你一直希望我做到的吗
Isn't this what you want for me?
你就不能至少信任我一次  让我试试吗
Can't you at least trust me enough to go try?
你难道想...和这个女孩离开吗
What, do you want to... run away with this girl?
我喜欢她
I like her.
你会杀死她的
You'll kill her.
我什么时候能见斯宾塞
When am I gonna meet Spencer?
快了  很快了
Soon. Very soon.
是他救了我  对吗
He's the one who saved me, right?
那他为什么怕见我
Why is he afraid to see me?
他不是害怕
Oh, he's not afraid.
斯宾塞只是...
Spencer is just--
害羞吗
Shy?
你说过了
Yeah, you said that.
我见过他和另一个女孩一起
I saw him with another girl.
他看上去
He doesn't, um,
他看上去好像并不害羞
he doesn't seem that shy.
是吗
Is that so?
她是谁
Who is she?
另一个女孩
The other girl.
没谁
Nobody.
只是一个邻居
Just a neighbor.
我保证
I assure you,
斯宾塞嘴里说的全是你
all Spencer does is talk about you.
等你记起了你是谁  你就明白了
You'll understand when you remember who you are.
是他帮助了你
He's the one who helped you.
那我们应该见一见
Then we should meet.
我想谢谢他
I-I wanna thank him.
什么声音
What was that?
我不知道
I don't know.
什么东西
What was it?
呼入  泰勒
这个会议一个月前就安排好了
This meeting has been on the books for over a month.
如果你今天不来  董事会会很...
If you don't come in today, the board is seriously--
这个大楼都是以我命名的
My name is on the building.
我肯定能有一些个人空间吧
Surely that gives me a little leeway here.
董事会的人已经到齐了  都在等你
The board is assembled and waiting for you.
-看上去情况不妙  -我的克隆组织
- It doesn't look good. - My cloned organs
将会给移植市场带来巨大的变革
are going to revolutionize the transplant market
为哈里斯基因带来巨大的财富
and make Harris Genetics wealthy beyond imagining.
你自己来和他们说
Come tell them that.
他们想当面和你谈
They want to see you face-to-face,
也许你能和我们说说你在你的家庭实验室里
and maybe you could give us a hint of what you're working on
都在做些什么  接下来我们...
in that home lab of yours, the next big thing we--
不  还不行
No, not yet.
赶紧过来
Come in, now.
和董事会聊聊
Talk to the board.
向他们保证我们公司的门面代表
Reassure them that the face of our company
会确保新产品的发布
will be there for the new product launches.
我马上来
I'm on my way.
结束通话
操
Fuck!
妈妈  你看到我的素描本了吗
Mom, have you seen my sketchbook?
别离开家  我要出去一趟
Don't leave the house, I need to go out.
-去哪里  -这不重要
- Where? - It doesn't matter.
在我回来之前  我会把艾什莉锁在她的房间里
I'm locking Ashley in her room until I get back.
为什么
Why?
因为我不信任你单独和她一起
Because I can't trust you alone with her.
我要去处理一些事
I need you to stay put for a few hours
你乖乖在这里待着
while I deal with something.
通缉
如果你看到此人  请联系我们
上帝啊  斯宾塞
Jesus Christ, Spencer,
你和这女孩在一起做什么
what the hell are you doing with this girl?
哈里斯基因
我已经尽量为你掩护了
I've been covering for you the best I can,
但是董事会关注的不仅仅是这个项目  还有你
but the board didn't just back this project, they backed you.
我知道  很抱歉我离开了这么久
I know, I'm sorry I've been gone.
玛丽莎·康奈尔
你家里的这个女孩子有故事
我的突破
The breakthroughs that I've made,
语言神经  物体识别
neural linguistics, object recognition,
全都能轰动世界
they're game-changers.
很好  那你去和他们说
Great, now go tell them.
信息监控
信息来自  玛丽莎·康奈尔
你家里的这个女孩子有故事
能不能稍等我一下
May I have just a moment?
-他们在等你  -就一会...
- They're waiting for you. - Just one quick--
你和她说了什么
What did you tell her?
我什么都没和她说
I didn't tell her anything.
我和你说了她是个麻烦  你就是不听我的
I told you she was trouble, you just wouldn't listen to me.
我知道
I know.
我马上回家
I'm coming right home.
我们不能再让他们继续等着了
We can't keep them waiting any longer.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我真的得走了
I really have to go.
你这是在犯下一个巨大的错误
You're making a huge mistake!
你来这里干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
你没有回我信息
You didn't answer my text.
斯宾塞  我知道有人和你一起住在这里
Spencer, I know that there's somebody here with you.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
艾什莉
Ashley.
她是叫这个名字  对吗
That's her name, isn't it?
她被通缉了
She's wanted.
你知道有人在找她吗
Do you know that people are looking for her?
她很危险
She's dangerous.
斯宾塞  怎么回事
Spencer, what's going on?
是她吗
Is that her?
是她  对吗
That's her, isn't it?
斯宾塞  我看到她了
Spencer, I saw her.
我拍了她的照片
I took her picture.
住手
Stop!
我本来打算改变了
I was gonna change.
为了你
For you.
本来不用变成这样的
It didn't have to end this way.
斯宾塞
Spencer!
住手  住手
Stop it! Stop it!
报警
Call 9-1-1!
正在报警
Dialing 9-1-1.
警察  请问有什么事
911, what's your emergency?
不
No!
女士  能听到我说话吗
Ma'am, can you hear me?
-斯宾塞  住手  -女士
- Spencer, stop, please! - Hello? Ma'am?
求你了  你不用这么做的
Please, you don't have to do this.
你不用这么做的
You don't have to do this!
-我必须这么做  -不不不
- I have to. - No, no, no, no.
不  不是的
No, you don't.
不管怎么样  我能帮你的  求你了
Whatever it is, I can help you. Please.
我是你的朋友  求你了
I'm your friend. Please.
斯宾塞
Spencer?
达到更像人类
更像机器
应用前景无限
外语种
知识量增加
潜在生物反馈/神经化学条件
不
No.
她本来准备报警
She was gonna call the cops.
我跟你说了不要去接近她
I told you to stay away from her!
她自己过来的  她...
She came over on her own, all right? She--
我想让她出去  但是她...
I tried to keep her out, but she just--
但是什么
But what?
她知道了
She knew.
-知道了多少  -她搜过了
- How much? - She ran a search.
她知道了关于艾什莉的一切
She knew everything about Ashley.
她手机上有照片
She had a picture on her phone,
是她和你一起
with you.
通缉
如果你看到此人  请联系我们
失踪
警察
三个未接来电
该死
Shit.
我们得处理掉尸体
We have to get rid of the bodies.
快点  去把艾什莉叫下来
Now! Go get Ashley!
艾什莉数据
语音信息
播放信息
我不在乎你遇上什么麻烦  亲爱的
I don't care what trouble you're in, honey,
回家吧
just please come home.
大家都在找你
Everyone's looking for you.
你在哪里  艾什莉
Where are you, Ashley?
你管发生了什么事  给我回电  好吗
Whatever's going on, just call me, okay?
她不在
She's not there.
她不在房间里
She's not in her room.
她在哪里
Well, where is she?
我们得找到她
Well, we have to find her.
警察随时都会来  我们得
The police are gonna be here any minute. We have to--
没事的  我就说都是我干的
It's okay, I'll take the heat.
我们就说都是我一个人干的
All right, we'll just say it was all me
这一切和你都没有关系
and you had nothing to do with any of this.
你这么关心我  我爱你  但是不行
I love you for thinking of me, but no.
我们一起承担
We do this together.
把尸体放到还原罐中
Okay, take this body to the tank.
我去实验室  打开生物分解仪
I will go to the lab and turn on the bio composter,
然后我们去找艾什莉
and then we will find Ashley.
她根本不熟悉这个地方
She doesn't know where she is.
她跑不了多远
She can't have gotten far.
冷静点
Easy.
我是谁
What am I?
你是
You're...
一个影子
a shadow.
一个人的记忆
A memory of someone.
不  我是我
No, I'm me.
不  你不是
No, you aren't.
你看过文件了  那你都知道了
You looked over the files, then you know.
-是我创造了你  -你不是我的母亲
- I made you. - You aren't my mother.
我给予了你生命  比你第一次
I gave you life, a better life
好上不知道多少倍的生活
than you ever would have had the first time around.
住口
Stop!
你看了多少
How much did you see?
你看到你自己是一名罪犯了吗
Did you read the part about being a criminal?
如果我儿子没有带你来
If my son hadn't taken you in,
你就会在监狱中腐烂  而不是...
you would be rotting in a cage instead--
而不是什么
Instead of what?
他杀了我多少次
How many times has he killed me?
你真的记了起来
You do remember.
我记得有手
I remember hands
还有窒息  还有他的脸
and choking and his face,
他变态的笑容
his sick fucking smile.
你们俩都是禽兽
You are monsters, both of you.
等等
Wait.
你是一个奇迹  你知道吗
You're a miracle, do you know that?
你是这个世界上
You are the rarest thing
最珍贵的东西
on this earth.
独一无二
Completely one-of-a-kind.
你不知道你有多么特别
You have no idea how special you are.
妈妈
Mom!
艾什莉
Ashley!
艾什莉  住手
Ashley, stop.
你要知道结局只能是这样的  对吗
You had to know it had to end this way, right?
你做了你力所能及能保护他的一切
You did everything you could to protect him.
他一开始就是破碎的
He was broken from the beginning.
我只是希望你能像我一样明白
I just wish you could've seen it as clearly as I did.
你需要放下
You need to put it to rest.
放下他吧  维多利亚
Let him go, Victoria.
就像你当初一样吗
Like you did?
我受够了
I'm done with this.
我要取出我的遣散费  卖掉房子
I'm taking my severance, selling the house.
你不会再联系到我了
You'll never hear from me again.
别这样  别...
Don't do this, don't--
你给我买了条狗吗
You got me a dog?
谢谢  妈妈  我爱你
Thanks, Mom, I love you.
我也爱你  宝贝
Oh, I love you too, sweetie.